Contact

s1759855@ed.ac.uk

+44 7722 003633

www.linkedin.com/in/sakib-a (LinkedIn)

www.sakib56.github.io (Personal Website)

Top Skills

Python

JavaScript

Java

Haskell

SQL

MATLAB

C/C++

Video Editing

Soft Skills

Management

Teamwork

Flexibility

Quick Learner

Confidence

Problem Solving

Sakib Ahamed

Penultimate Year BSc. Artificial Intelligence Student, The University of Edinburgh

Summary

A hardworking third year Artificial Intelligence student with prior experience in industries related to financial technology and banking software. Strong knowledge of the software development cycle, as well as proficiency in multiple programming languages. Works well under pressure, in teams, and has a love for mathematics and problem solving.

Experience

Allatus Ltd

Junior Software Developer

September 2018 - Present (1 year 5 months)

Software Development Intern
May 2018 - September 2018 (5 months)
Edinburgh, United Kingdom

I am responsible for enhancing Allatus' FinTech web applications using JavaScript, HTML & Elasticsearch in conjunction with the Dojo Toolkit. I develop front-end algorithms and features as well as fix bugs. In addition, I update documentation, create and edit videos, ensuring that all media content is both coherent and up to date with the latest builds of Allatus Unity. I am currently diversifying to work on the back-end using C# and SQL databases. After my initial internship, I was taken on as a part-time software developer whilst simultaneously completing my studies.

The Three Sisters Pub & Restaurant Runner
June 2017 - August 2017 (3 month)
Edinburgh, United Kingdom

While I worked in the fast-paced environment of the Three Sisters, I developed time management skills, and learned to filter tasks by importance, to complete my many duties. These included introducing guests to the venue, giving me experience of dealing with customers face-to-face, as well as stocking and preparing food for the outdoor barbeque.

Amazon

Event Assistant

May 2017 - May 2017 (1 month)

Edinburgh, United Kingdom

Previously I worked at an Amazon Conference at the EICC. Which involved catering to the needs of a wide range of people. By doing this, I developed my skills in networking and teamwork, as many tasks involved arranging the catering services and organising and directing large groups of business delegates. I also had the chance to be a host and represent the company, which allowed me to further improve my interpersonal skills.

Boardwalk Beach Club Café Waiter

June 2016 - July 2016 (2 months)

Edinburgh, United Kingdom

In the past I worked at a café where I did a variety of different tasks which includes both serving customers at the till and waiting tables. As this was my first job, I gained a lot of confidence and people skills. I worked with a diverse range of people from different cultures which has helped improve my teamwork and collaboration abilities.

Education

The University of Edinburgh

Third Year, Bachelor of Science, Artificial Intelligence · (2017 - 2021)

- 2:1 Predicted
- Edinburgh Award for Global Insights Week (Singapore)
- Noteworthy Courses:
 - Data and Analysis (82%)
 - Computer Security (74%)
 - Reasoning and Agents (72%)
 - Applied Machine Learning (70%)
 - Foundations of Natural Language Processing (70%)

The Royal High School (2011 - 2017)

- AAAABC Scottish Highers
- Dux of Mathematics
- James H Scott Award for Mathematics